Tom Paulin papers, 1972-2008
Emory University
- Printed material, Series 5; Boxes 59-60
  The series includes a variety of printed material including materials by and about Tom Paulin, as well as general printed material. It should be noted that Series 2 and Series 3 also include some printed material.
  Arranged into three sections: Printed material by Tom Paulin, Printed material about Tom Paulin, and General printed material.
  - Printed material by Tom Paulin
  - Poems printed in newspapers (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - Reviews printed in newspapers (Box 59, Folder 2)
  - "Dwelling without Roots: Elizabeth Bishop" in Grand Street 36, 1990 (Box 59, Folder 3)
  - "My Country Childhood" in Country Living, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous clippings (Box 59, Folder 5)
  - Printed material about Tom Paulin
  - Newspaper clippings about Tom Paulin (Box 59, Folder 6)
  - [Untitled] Interview with Tom Paulin by Suma Jossen in The Sunday Observer (Bombay), 17 January 1988 (Box 59, Folder 7)
  - "The Civil War is still going on" by Valentine Cunningham in The Observer, 12 January 1992 (Box 59, Folder 8)
  - "Discord in corduroy" by Eamonn Rafferty in The Daily Telegraph, 21 October 1994 (Box 59, Folder 9)
  - "The Plain Speaker" [interview with Tom Paulin] in Graph 3.2, Autumn/Winter 1998 (Box 59, Folder 10)
  - "Poetic License" by Stephen Moss in The Guardian, 16 May 2000 (Box 59, Folder 11)
  - General printed material
  - Printed material with literary subjects (Box 59, Folder 12)
  - Printed material with literary subjects (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - Other printed material (Box 60, Folder 2)
  - Other printed material (Box 60, Folder 3)
  - Other printed material (Box 60, Folder 4)
- Photographs and audiovisual material, Series 6; Boxes 61-66
  This series includes photographs, videotapes, and audiocassettes. All of the videotapes are of Paulin's appearances on the "Late Review" BBC 2 program; most of the audiocassettes involve critical commentary by Tom Paulin.
  - Photographs
  - Photographs of Tom Paulin (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - Other photographs (Box 61, Folder 2)
  - Late Review materials
  - Itineraries and correspondence (Box 61, Folder 3)
  - Notes by Tom Paulin (Box 61, Folder 4)
  - Notebooks [4] (Box 61, Folder 5)
  - Printed materials (Box 61, Folder 6)
  - Late Review Videotapes
  - 18 September 1997 (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - 25 September 1997 (Box 62, Folder 2)
  - 2 October 1997 (Box 62, Folder 3)
  - 9 October 1997 (Box 62, Folder 4)
  - 16 October 1997 (Box 62, Folder 5)
  - 30 October 1997 [damaged] (Box 62, Folder 6)
  - 6 November 1997 (Box 62, Folder 7)
  - 13 November 1997 (Box 62, Folder 8)
  - 11 December 1997 (Box 62, Folder 9)
  - 22 January 1998 (Box 62, Folder 10)
  - 29 January 1998 (Box 62, Folder 11)
  - 26 February 1998 (Box 62, Folder 12)
  - 5 March 1998 (Box 62, Folder 13)
  - 12 March 1998 (Box 62, Folder 14)
  - 19 March 1998 (Box 62, Folder 15)
  - 27 March 1998 (Box 63, Folder 1)
  - 9 April 1998 (Box 63, Folder 2)
  - 7 May 1998 (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - 14 May 1998 (Box 63, Folder 4)
  - 21 May 1998 (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - 28 May 1998 (Box 63, Folder 6)
  - 17 September 1998 (Box 63, Folder 7)
  - 24 September 1998 (Box 63, Folder 8)
  - 8 October 1998 (Box 63, Folder 9)
  - 15 October 1998 [2 tapes] (Box 63, Folder 10)
  - 5 November 1998 (Box 63, Folder 11)
  - 12 November 1998 (Box 63, Folder 12)
  - 10 December 1998 (Box 63, Folder 13)
  - 14 January 1999 (Box 64, Folder 1)
  - 21 January 1999 (Box 64, Folder 2)
  - 28 January 1999 (Box 64, Folder 3)
  - 4 February 1999 (Box 64, Folder 4)
  - 17 February 1999 (Box 64, Folder 5)
  - 4 March 1999 (Box 64, Folder 6)
  - 18 March 1999 (Box 64, Folder 7)
  - 6 May 1999 (Box 64, Folder 8)
  - 12 May 1999 (Box 64, Folder 9)
  - 16 September 1999 (Box 64, Folder 10)
  - 23 September 1999 [2 copies] (Box 64, Folder 11)
  - 30 September 1999 (Box 64, Folder 12)
  - 7 October 1999 (Box 64, Folder 13)
  - n.d. ["Welcome to Sarajevo" reviewed] (Box 64, Folder 14)
  - Audiocassettes involving Tom Paulin
  - "Before History" [Music composed by Martin Read, based on poem by Tom Paulin; Sylvia Harper, solo oboe] (Box 65, Folder 1)
  - "Best Words" [BBC Radio 3 program; Tom Paulin discusses the poetry of Arthur Hugh Clough] (Box 65, Folder 2)
  - "Centurions: 'In Memory of W. B. Yeats' by W.H. Auden" [BBC Radio 3 program involving Tom Paulin] (Box 65, Folder 3)
  - "Conversation" [radio program; by Tom Paulin] [See also Series 2.5: Scripts] (Box 65, Folder 4)
  - "Englands of the Mind" [Open University Production; Tom Paulin and others respond to Seamus Heaney's essay on Philip Larkin, Ted Hughes and Geoffrey Hill] (Box 65, Folder 5)
  - "Fine Lines: Episode 5" [BBC Radio 4; presented by Christopher Cook with Tom Paulin and Piotr Sommer; 19 July 1998] (Box 65, Folder 6)
  - "John Clare" [Artworks production; Tom Paulin contributes] (Box 65, Folder 7)
  - "The Loyalist Response to the Anglo-Irish Agreement" [1986 lecture at Oxford "Irony and Carnival" conference; Terry Eagleton introduces; Paulin followed by Edna Longley lecture on poetry and politics in Northern Ireland] (Box 65, Folder 8)
  - "Men of Letters" [BBC Radio 4 series on poetry and letters; Tom Paulin on Side B] (Box 65, Folder 9)
  - "National Poetry Day: A Book of Hours" [BBC Radio 4; Tom Paulin reads "Folly Bridge"] (Box 65, Folder 10)
  - "Oscar Wilde" [radio program; Tom Paulin contributes] (Box 65, Folder 11)
  - "Poetry and the End of Empire: Philip Larkin and Ted Hughes" [Open University Production; Tom Paulin and Donald Davie discuss Philip Larkin's poetry] (Box 65, Folder 12)
  - "Poets of the Month: Tom Paulin" [BBC Radio 3, February 1992; parts 1 and 2] (Box 65, Folder 13)
  - "Poets of the Month: Tom Paulin" [BBC Radio 3, February 1992; parts 1-4] (Box 65, Folder 14)
  - "Postscript: A Poem for Ireland" [Tom Paulin reads a selection of his poetry: 20 March 1998] (Box 65, Folder 15)
  - "Prometheus Bound" [radio program; Tom Paulin discusses his Seize the Fire] (Box 65, Folder 16)
  - "The Protestant Mind" [BBC Radio 4 Program; Tom Paulin contributes] (Box 65, Folder 17)
  - Seize The Fire by Tom Paulin [BBC Radio 3 Production] [2 copies] (Box 65, Folder 18)
  - "Sound and Poetry" [Radio program, 4 August 1992; Tom Paulin contributes] (Box 65, Folder 19)
  - Untitled [on Creative Writing Programs in U.S.A; includes interviews with Tom Paulin, Seamus Heaney and Thomas Flanagan] (Box 65, Folder 20)
  - Untitled [radio program; Tom Paulin discusses his Faber Book of Vernacular Verse] (Box 65, Folder 21)
  - Untitled [Radio Oxford program; Tom Paulin discusses Seamus Heaney's work] (Box 65, Folder 22)
  - Untitled [Radio Oxford program; Bernard O'Donoghue discusses Tom Paulin's Minotaur] (Box 65, Folder 23)
  - Untitled [Side 1: Tom Paulin reviews William Trevor's Family Sins and Other Stories, 25 January 1990; Side 2: Tom Paulin reviews Brian Friel's Translations, 13 May 1981] (Box 65, Folder 24)
  - Other audiocassettes
  - "Bailegangaire" by Tom Murphy [Radio play] (Box 65, Folder 25)
  - "United Irishmen" [Radio program on Tone Wolfe; 14 November 1998] (Box 65, Folder 26)
  - "Varieties of Irishness" [Seamus Heaney talk for The Ireland Fund, n.d.] (Box 65, Folder 27)
  - "The White, The Gold and the Gangrene" by Terry Eagleton [Radio play, broadcast on Radio 3] (Box 65, Folder 28)
  - Untitled [Elizabeth Bishop reads her poetry] (Box 65, Folder 29)
  - Untitled [Seamus Heaney interviewed re. North] (Box 65, Folder 30)
  - Various sermons [most by Ian Paisley; 8 cassettes, mostly "Martyrs Memorial Recordings"] (Box 66, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous and unidentified cassettes [11 cassettes; includes 1 empty cassette case entitled "Poetry and Revolution"] (Box 66, Folder 2)
- Personal files, Series 7; Box 67
  The series includes personal materials relating to Tom Paulin. It should be noted that there are some diary entries in Tom Paulin's notebooks, which can be found in Subseries 2.1.
  - Appointment diaries, 1982-1989 (Box 67, Folder 1)
  - Appointment diaries, 1990-1997 (Box 67, Folder 2)
  - Address book (Box 67, Folder 3)
  - Family correspondence (Box 67, Folder 4)
  - Recommendation letters about Tom Paulin (Box 67, Folder 5)
  - University of Hull, Calendar 1969-1970 [photocopy] (Box 67, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 67, Folder 7)
- Subject files, Series 8; Boxes 68-69, OP 7
  The series consists of subject files which contain discrete groups of information which could not easily be assimilated into other series. Many of Tom Paulin's subject files concern research on Protestantism and Romanticism.
  - Larkin letters, correspondence and printed material [See also Subseries 2.5, Scripts: “Philip Larkin”] (Box 68, Folder 1)
  - Research notes on Arthur Hugh Clough (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - Research materials on William Drennan (Box 68, Folder 3)
  - Research notes on Romanticism (Box 68, Folder 4)
  - Research notes on Romanticism (Box 68, Folder 5)
  - Research notes on Unitarianism (Box 68, Folder 6)
  - Research notes on Unitarianism (Box 69, Folder 1)
  - Loyalist printed material (Box 69, Folder 2)
  - Ian Paisley archive [printed materials and pamphlets] (Box 69, Folder 3)
  - Ian Paisley archive [printed materials and pamphlets] (Box 69, Folder 4)
  - Ian Paisley archive [printed materials and pamphlets] (Box 69, Folder 5)
  - Northern Irish political posters (Box OP7)
- Unprocessed additions, Series 10; Boxes 70-84, OP8
  - Mixed material (Box 70-82)
  - Audiovisual material (Box 82-84)
  - Printed material (Box OP8)
  - Mixed material (Box 85)